[jazz music]
[Peter] Good morning, guys, Philadelphia,
the city known as
the birthplace of America.
The Declaration of Independence,
the Constitution,
the promise of freedom.
So today we're gonna
get out in the city 250 years
after this beautiful experiment kicked off.
Get the lay of the land,
talk to the locals,
see what things are like now.
-Oh man, great to meet you in person.
-Great to meet you.
Are you visiting the park?
I'm doing a video for
the country's birthday.
-Pretty busy, huh?
-Yes.
This is our security line
just to get into the square.
Gotta start at the starting point,
Declaration of Independence,
-Then the Constitution.
-11 years later.
-Drafted by Jefferson, right?
-Exactly.
He spent two and a half weeks,
he and the committee of five drafting it.
They submitted their draft here June 28th
to the larger congress.
That's so crazy, two and a half weeks?
-Thank you so much. Great meeting you.
-Great to meet you.
Independence Hall from the front side.
We'll walk over to the Liberty Bell.
This isn't going to be
much of a history tour today, guys.
But had to start it here.
We're gonna get to
as many corners of this city as we can
in the daylight hours.
-Croatian YouTube?
-Yeah.
In New York.
-What are you shooting?
-Travel.
-Travel videos? Nice.
-Yeah.
-You got the big game tonight?
-I'm going to game, yeah.
-All right.
-You are also YouTuber?
-Yeah, I make videos.
-Name of channel?
-It's Peter Santenello.
-So big deal for your country today?
-Yeah.
We will win definitely.
-You're gonna win?
-Yeah.
-[man] My buddy loves you, can I do…
-Let's do it.
-Peter Santenello?
-That guy, yeah.
Say, "Hey John."
Hey, John, what's going on?
Why aren't you here?
-Your buddies are waiting for you.
-Thank yo so much.
You having a good time for the birthday?
Oh yeah, we're going all over the place,
we just went to Shady Maple.
Just came here, going to New Haven after.
-Where you guys from?
-Chicago.
Nice.
Okay, here we have it, the Liberty Bell.
[tour guide] One of the many
relics of the revolution.
By giving the name the Liberty Bell…
What do we say
when we say all men are created equal?
That includes the enslaved.
The bell gave
the American people a purpose.
that maybe just independence didn't infer.
This bell became
something more than it began with
and the irony is we have people here
for the World Cup.
The irony is that
if we weren't wearing our t shirts
or our Croatia jerseys
I couldn't tell where any of you were from.
You want a symbol
for liberty throughout the world…
It's a cracked bell from 1752.
Gotta love the passion of that guy.
That was amazing.
So many of these guys working
in museums like this
are really passionate, fired up
on what they're doing
and sharing the stories here.
Love it.
All right, let's hit the streets.
Let's get out there.
That's gonna be
most of the history for today.
-Peter.
-How you doing, bro?
-Juan, right?
-Yes sir.
-How's it going, Juan?
-It's going, man.
Trying to stay happy.
-You from Philly?
-I am.
-You love your city?
-Love and hate.
-Love and hate, okay.
-Love and hate relationship.
I'm sure that's with everyone.
Philly's vibrant, Philly's good.
Given the atmosphere,
what's going on in the world,
people are still
a little bit hopeful, right?
-Okay.
You have to have
good energy to continue in this world.
Can't control the things
you cannot control.
So what are you gonna do?
Ball into a corner or keep moving forward?
-I move forward with good energy.
-Yeah.
-This is Rittenhouse, this whole strip.
-Okay, up here?
-That park you may want to walk through.
-I'll check it out.
-The Amish are in town.
They're selling stuff so you're good.
-Thank you so much.
Oh, look at this.
This is Rittenhouse Square.
Nice part of town.
The Amish are here and you can see
this woman is Amish with her bonnet.
And so the reason why
so many Amish came to Pennsylvania is
because William Penn,
the founder of the state
created a place of true religious freedom
and incentivised the Amish
to come from Europe.
because he knew
they were fantastic farmers.
That's what they did. They came in droves.
Went out to Lancaster County, Pennsylvania.
Rolling hills, beautiful farmland.
Set up shop and now they've multiplied.
There's a ton out there today
and many also in Holmes County
where I've made Amish videos.
What a place. Look at this.
Let's see if we can
talk to one of these guys.
-How you doing, sir?
-Good.
How's it going?
Good. Nice morning.
-Can I record all this? Is that okay?
-Sure.
Okay.
As long as I keep working.
-Are you old order, new order?
-Old order, yes.
-Old Oder?
-So steel wheels on the carriages?
-That's right.
Keeping it real.
-You come here for the farmers markets?
-Every Saturday.
-How's it working out?
-Really good.
It's incredible.
Love bringing joy into the city.
-Fantastic.
So Pennsylvania's
a great agricultural state
Not far from here,
fruits and vegetables grown.
Lot of small farms, organic stuff.
Got blueberries, plums, strawberries, pies.
Amish pies are the best in my opinion.
A lot of foreigners
when they come to the US,
and we see a lot with the World Cup
they see Taco Bell.
They get excited about all the chains
which I guess a lot of them,
are new to them.
But what many don't know
is we do have a thriving food world here
with good natural products
and a lot of craft, and heart and soul,
put into things like home brew
or fresh baked pastries
or just really good organic vegetables.
And that's my old school Vermont
hippie side coming out right now.
I really love that stuff.
I love to see that.
So you're not seeing
any of the jerseys over here.
We got the game tonight.
We're gonna check that out.
Not get in but get into the environment
and get around the stadium.
See what that energy's like.
But this is old money up here.
So we're roughly 10
minutes from where we started.
And this is more of a residential Philly.
More of a lived here
for generations type Philly.
There's a great vibe in this city
and look at these old beauties.
So much cool architecture here.
Just think, really not that long ago.
This country is three lifetimes old.
That's just wild to think of.
That's when Benjamin Franklin
and Thomas Jefferson, and Adams,
they were all walking these streets
figuring out what the country's gonna be.
How it's gonna be different
from leaving the monarchies of Europe.
Giving independence to the people
and creating a place where
really anyone can become American.
There are a few countries in the world
where someone can truly
become that identity.
But if I moved to China or Japan
no matter how well I speak the language,
never gonna be Chinese or Japanese.
Doesn't mean they won't take me in
but the identity of America,
that's something new in human history
where if you're a citizen you're a citizen.
Doesn't matter where you're from,
what you look like.
You can just walk these streets
and run into this stuff
left and right.
Listen to that.
Gets silent.
No more noise from the streets,
just a few fans.
[whispers] Wow, what a beauty.
This place is great.
Little village feel to it.
Bunch of storefronts.
I'm sure some great restaurants out here.
Even some old school stuff
like ACM Quality paints, Lee's Hardware
That' what you want to see
in these neighborhoods.
That some of the old school
businesses can still make it.
Can't imagine the price of these places.
You know what, I think I gotta get a bike.
This is the way to do it.
Rain's not stopping anyone.
Another nice little park.
Look at those gardens.
River Park Community Garden.
Bringing the doggos out.
They're all so well behaved.
You can see the jerseys coming out.
Lot of Croatia representation.
Look at these guys.
They're on a mission.
There's some Ghana fans.
Art Deco beauty right there.
It has such a unique feel to it, Philly.
The architecture's all over the place.
You have all that finance over there,
all the men high up in the suits.
Big businesses
but then this historical element to it.
Which really makes it special.
Philly's got a Chinatown.
They're putting the flags out
for the birthday.
[man yelling] California! California!
[distorted loudspeaker]
-In Japan!
-Brother and sisters.
-Ladies and gentlemen.
-Listen to me carefully.
-God already…
-[traffic drowns out speaker]
[busker's music plays]
[singing Just the Way You Are
by Billy Joel]
-[Peter] Thank you, sir.
-Thank you. Appreciate you.
This place is awesome right now.
It is fired up.
It's such a mix.
That's what makes Philly and New York,
the big US cities,
so fascinating.
The best people watching.
You don't know what's around the next turn.
This is the Reading Terminal Market.
Just a ton of food and shops around here.
This place is thriving right now.
Italian sausages, I don't know what else.
What do you go going on here, sir?
Some of the best ginger in Philadelphia.
First ginger shop
in Philadelphia since 1776.
-You serious?
We started with
cold pressed ginger beverage
they all have 20 gram of real ginger,
white caps have cane sugar,
black and green, zero sugar, zero
sweetener, but we increase the ingredients.
-I'll try one with the no sugar.
-How's your city these days?
-It's interesting.
How so?
The economy is still down.
Yet in a city like Philadelphia we still
continue to put our best foot forward.
-It's got a lot of energy right now.
-Always has.
That's why so many people
continue to come here.
-For those that don't know, what is
special about Philly? What is the vibe?
It's the people, yeah.
It's bigger than the nice buildings
and being America's first.
There are lineages of people
that you could just never
get anywhere else.
-Like this market for example.
-This is wild.
133 years old, right?
Most of these places
are family run, generations of family.
-No way.
What's the story with this market?
Trains used to come right in here.
-Oh, this is a train station?
-Right in here.
-Okay, gotcha.
Where you see markets, that's how it was,
folks wouldsell their goods.
All right.
So Really Real Ginger.
I like that RX.
Like a little medicine.
What do we have in here?
-Ginger.
Lemon, water, a little vanilla.
-Mmm.
-Oh, mint.
Equally balanced, perfect.
Not sweet, I got the non-sweetened version.
That's good, my friend.
-And over 20 grams of real ginger.
-Take care.
-Looking forward to your content.
Thank you.
That's good.
That is nice.
We got Thai food.
We've got Wilt's.
Don't know what that is, chocolate.
Some more Amish representation.
They make great things.
If an Amish person
can build your barn, or shed, or house,
you're a lucky person
'cause that's what you want.
They do quality work.
[man] Come in to the right!
[Peter] Number seven!
So Gus's is a local favorite I believe.
We're not gonna wait in that line
but what we're gonna do now is…
well, if you've seen my videos before,
you know we're not gonna
keep in the nice touristy areas
so we're gonna jump the tracks,
go to another part of Philly,
and then come back for the action.
The build up to the game.
And catch those festivities.
But before then
we're going on a little mission.
A little pit stop here, guys.
At the Simon and Schuster Warehouse.
We're gonna see my book
for the first time together
-How you doing?
-Good, how are you doing?
-Doing well. Exciting day.
-[laughs]
-When did my book get in?
-Thursday.
-Waiting out here for you.
-Oh, cool. Wow!
Look at this.
-This is the pallets of your book.
-No way.
-These are all my book?
-These are all your book.
Someone already broke into 'em.
[laughter]
Guilty, yeah.
-Mike, you're going camera man.
-Sure.
All right, the big moment.
-Here you go.
[laughter]
All right. Here it is.
Everyone, Your Fellow Americans.
Okay, all the spelling's right,
we're good on that.
Doesn't say your fellow Mexicans.
-It's been proofread. [laughs]
Wow, I love the feel of this too.
-Yeah.
It's got a glossy feel and then hear that?
[scraping]
It's got texture.
-Goosebumps.
Haven't gotten those in a while.
So there you go, guys,
pre-order Your Fellow Americans.
It goes live on August 4th.
QR code here, link down below.
Also the book tour is happening.
Gonna be in New York, Boston,
Greater Chicago, Greater Detroit,
Greater Phoenix.
We just added LA and more dates coming.
So hope to see you
at one of those signings.
We'll all hang out.
It'll be great to see you in person.
Thanks, you guys.
This is a special day.
Without these guys, none of this happens.
Hey, don't walk out.
-You're back in there.
-[laughter]
Without these guys, none of this happens.
This is behind the scenes
of how the book world works.
Not only is it the editors,
and the book cover designers,
it's the people that actually facilitate
you getting the book.
Huge operation with a lot of logistics.
and hard-working passionate people
-So thank you guys.
-Thank you.
[Peter] Malcom, born and raised in Philly.
How's it going right now?
Just doing a little Uber today.
It's the World Cup going on,
a lot going on in the city.
So what have you been doing, Malcom?
You've got your own what?
Luxury designer brand
called Savage Series 8.
Got New York Fashion Week
coming up in September.
-Nice, you wearing these clothes?
This is one of my sweatsuits,
it's one of one, custom made.
Nobody else got this.
Do you think I could get away with
wearing that? Could I pull that off?
Yeah, you got style.
You're being nice, Malcom.
I got a black shirt and dorky shoes.
-But you love your city?
-Of course, for sure.
I was born in the inner city.
So that's even more of a way
to see how Philly have grown
in so many years.
It's unbelievable to even see it
'cause it's such a hustle mentality city.
The grit, the culture.
-So we're cruising to North Philly.
It's got the bad reputation, right?
Or depends where you're at?
-Depends where you're at
because so many people outside the city
that's coming…
Like New York, outside the city's
coming to move here.
-There's a new building site there now.
-Oh, yeah.
Growing up inner city, to get to a point
on some sense of happiness,
is far fetched because resources,
there's not a wide range
versus the suburb part.
Even a lot of schools that got closed down.
A lot of public schools have closed down.
-Okay, I was asking off camera,
but why are you so positive?
-Because coming from a city like Philly,
where it can seem like
crabs in a barrel mentality,
you gotta have that positive
'cause that's what keeps you going.
Something to look forward to.
Accomplishing a goal.
That's why I like positivity, it helps.
Versus looking at the other side
like someone sleeping in the street
or got a needle in they arm.
So growing up in North Philly
when you having that positive spirit
or positive mindset can help.
-Malcom, you gonna go off the clock
and cruise
-You wanna do that?
-Let's go. It's completed.
Five star rating, let's go.
-Fishtown is that way?
-Fishtown is that way.
If you went down Richmond Street,
and got on 95 and off at Girad.
-Girard.
-Girard, okay.
Girad?
And take that right down
-All in there.
-No, speak deep Philly for me.
-Girad, right?
-Girad.
Girad, all right.
-Get a waadaw.
-Get a waadaw, get a cawfee, getoudahere.
-That's Jersey I'm speaking.
-[laughter]
Cawfee, okay.
So Fishtown is thriving,
there's restaurants, it's going on.
-All kinds of restaurants.
-All kinds of people.
They're moving from New York
'cause it's expensive.
-They're moving in?
All right, I live in
a 980 square foot roho.
Lived there 30 years.
The house next door to me,
same size.
-Yeah.
-No parking, schools suck.
If your kids don't play soccer you gotta do
everything outside the neighborhood.
-385.
-Wow.
-Okay, then I'm gonna go to Kensington.
What are your thoughts there?
Kensington is so sad.
We don't even recognize our streets
but they did flip my mom and dad's house.
Looks nice inside but…
I was there two years ago, still as bad?
-Yeah.
-Yep.
Really? They haven't changed it?
When the new mayor came in
probably for like two months,
"We're cleaning up Kensington Ave."
-They did nothing.
-For one day.
They're all zombies.
-It's bad.
-It's sad.
-Very sad.
-Okay.
Across the street at Melrose Drug store,
and they were selling…
Train right across the street. That's K&A!
-Trotting over drug addicts.
-Yeah.
It's actually sad.
Have you been? Are you from here?
Yeah, born and raised.
-Where at?
-North 23rd and Leon.
Okay.
-Nadavis High School.
-Okay.
-What do you think of his fashion line?
That's his fashion line.
-I think it looks nice.
-Thank you.
My grandson would wear that.
Kensington always had a bit
of a reputation in the 70s.
And it wasn't bad.
-So what happened?
Manufacturing jobs went away?
-All the manufacturing jobs.
-Everything.
And then people start
just selling their property.
Everybody, you know…
I was born and raised there.
-Malcom lives in the 'burbs now.
I live Delaware County now.
Do you like it?
I used to really love Philly,
"I'll never leave" but it's getting bad.
-But they're making us leave.
-Yeah.
You feel like you're getting pushed out?
-I got pushed out of three neighborhoods.
-My property tax used to be $600.
When I went up to $1,000
I said we can't complain
we paid $600 all these years.
Now they're $4,000.
-Are you serious?
They give you nothing.
She's Fishtown,
I'm Port Richmond, I'm $2,800.
-You're 28 years old?
-No… Oh, yeah…
-[laughter]
-I had a hard life.
You're looking great.
-But you see people.
-My taxes are lower than hers.
There's nurses down there
that used to be professionals.
-Right.
-It's sad.
-And Kenny…
Malcom, you want to get out of the rain?
Actually there's no cover here.
-We good.
-We good. We good.
You're hair's…
When Kenny was the mayor…
Listen, when Kenny did K&A
cleaned it up 'cause someone was coming.
-Yeah.
They start walking around
our neighborhoods.
Trying to get my water on
in front of my house.
-Okay.
Somebody came, I don't remember who it was.
That was done, they were all right back
-So what about World Cup?
You excited or no?
I ain't watching.
I mean this is like another world
from downtown, right?
-Yeah, yeah.
-Yeah.
-When you go down where I'm at…
-And you go like in…
-Very preppy.
Down on Frankford Ave.
there's all kinds of world games.
-Okay.
There's all kinds of festivities.
Bye.
Take care, ladies.
-What do you got here?
-Soft pretzels.
Yeah, sure.
Thank you. Philly pretzels.
That's Philly staple.
Thank you.
You'll never get a better pretzel.
A summer dinner. Have fun.
See ya, ladies. Thank you.
-First Philly pretzel?
-Yeah.
These the menace.
These pretzels win.
You got the big one.
If you can get 'em
when they first warm even better.
-Nice, Malcom.
Did you think when you clocked in today
you'd be walking around in the rain
eating Philly pretzels?
-Talking to the ladies?
-You know…
It's always an adventure with Uber.
You never know what's gonna happen.
I look at it as like
doing Uber's already
an adventure in itself.
So why not further the adventure
with someone else that's adventurous?
You just gotta go with it
We're getting rained out.
[Peter] Malcom had to take a call.
But these neighborhoods just go on forever.
That used to be a German church.
This is a Polish, Irish neighborhood.
-Block party, is that what's going on?
-Yeah, it's a block party for…
It's the baby's birthday, she's four.
-Oh, that's cool.
-Right, Harley?
-You okay with her on camera?
-I don't know.
Dad, is she okay to be on camera?
-He's on a YouTube thing.
-Go ahead.
You sure?
He's a YouTube channel dude.
I've seen him a million times.
-Tag my company in it.
-What's your company?
-One Step Contracting.
-You're doing building, concrete?
-How's it going?
-Good.
I've seen him go to different states
and he's been in Philly for a minute
and he does a lot of stuff in Philly,
what's going on here and there.
Not like the news people
know the realities ofthe neighborhoods
-What do the news people get wrong here?
They don't know
their boundaries of the city. You
gotta be in here to know
where the boundaries are for the city.
-Is it okay if I stay under here?
-Yeah. Get in there.
Don't call this Kensington on the news.
-Don't call this Kensington?
-Yes!
No. No.
Don't call this Kensington
and don't call the other side Aramingo,
Port Richmond, it's not. That's Jasper!
-What is this?
-Port Richmond!
Port Richmond!
-This is part of the River Ward, Pennsport,
Port Richmond, Bridesburg.
We're all the River Ward.
Are you guys getting fired up
for the birthday?
I keep flags all day every day.
Irish ones and…
Back to back.
-That's your place?
-Yes.
-You're doing a great job.
-Philly is where it all started.
-Of course we're about the 250.
-The origin story.
Philly's many things, huh?
I was in Rittenhouse Park.
-That's a different feeling.
-Totally different.
-It's a lot more money.
-That's the elite.
Dude that tries to run for mayor
all the time, Dom.
Dom's son, you know who I'm talking about?
He owns half of Rittenhouse Square.
He got some good ideas for to be mayor
but nobody wants to put him in
because of his money, money, money.
But they keep putting these nitwits in
like who's in there right now.
Should be fired.
Because she gave millions of dollars
to hire on people
that don't need to be there
and did not give
the street cleaners, the…
My husband works for the water department.
He's a necessary person!
Let me ask you this,
what's the price of these places
right now roughly?
-Average probably $300,000.
-When we bought, 30 grand.
You bought 30 grand?
30 to 60 grand 20 years ago.
That's what you gotta ask,
the real price or what it is now?
-Gamer Mason?
-Now it's ridiculous.
-$300,000 average.
-You found me.
You found me, thanks, buddy.
Appreciate it.
-60 years.
-You been here 60 years?
Yes, my mom and I shared a house together.
-My mom just passed away.
-I'm sorry.
Thank you. But I love it.
I will not live in another neighborhood.
Port Richmond
is the best neighborhood around.
-It's a good community?
-Yes.
-I mean you literally take over the street.
And the neighbors help.
I mean I'm disabled.
-You guys got each other's backs?
-All day.
-All day?
-It's a family here.
It's almost like
country living in that sense.
-Kinda.
-In the city.
Everyone knows everyone.
Oh yeah, yeah.
Or if not just go talk to them.
-We're all friendly.
-Is it safe here?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We all got each other's back.
No bullsh*t going on around here.
Nothing.
When the bullsh*t comes
we make sure it goes away.
Yeah, 'cause we've had
crack houses on this block.
Over the last 20 years.
As a disabled person
the neighbors all have my back.
When I need something they'll tell me
okay, do you need me?
-This our girl right here.
She's a legend.
-Legend?
I can see straight in her house
if I want to so she gotta close her blinds
just so I know she's safe.
'Cause I live there, and she lives there.
If I open my door
I can almost see in her house.
I moved here four months ago,
it's like family.
You wouldn't know
I moved here four months ago.
I didn't know them from nothing.
-You guys brought him in?
-I'm the biggest b*tch of all.
She brought me in. You're the biggest
b*tch east of the Mississippi?
-East of the Mississippi.
-How'd you let him in?
He's a young buck and he's from
the neighborhood so he knows the rules.
-Exactly.
-What are the rules?
The rules are don't be an a**hole.
You know what I mean?
To your neighbors, don't be ignorant.
-Look out for each other.
-Right.
That's the code around here, man.
If you're gonna have stuff, keep it up.
You want some good video,
go down K&A, man.
-I'm going to Kensington right now.
-Be careful though, man.
Yeah, watch your back.
Watch your back down there.
-Love what you got going on here.
Thank you.
-Pray for sun!
-McPherson Square Park, I know that place.
-Have a good one.
-You too.
Dude, that was awesome.
It's like it's own world down there.
We call Philly its own country
a little bit.
Yeah, right.
Straight ahead is the K&A Zombieland
if you wanna go there.
-Let's do Zombieland.
'Cause I haven't been there.
I did a video almost two years ago.
I was with a guy that's bringing kids
off the streets
through boxing and religion.
And I liked his mission
as in he's trying to help the place.
I want to see
what it's like two years later.
[sirens blare]
[Peter] Geez, man.
So kids jut gotta walk through this stuff?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
Imagine how can you be
happy from seeing this every day.
-No, it's a heavy energy here obviously.
Okay, so why do you think
the city has not fixed this issue.
They're not gonna allow this to happen
in other parts of the city.
I mean people doing what they doing.
How can you stop
when people doing what they doing.
You stop it by
not allowing it on the streets
So for example, I'll get pushback,
someone will say,
well hey don't put 'em in prison.
I understand that argument.
I think you need therapy
or prison, right?
You need treatment, psychiatric therapy.
I mean…
It's just not humanity.
Like they're just on fent nodding off.
It's awful.
That's the way to the train. Holy sh*t!
It's unacceptable.
Okay, so my point is this,
you gotta get people
out of this environment.
This isn't compassion.
Right? Look at that guy in the wheelchair.
In front of the health center.
Yeah, in front of the health center.
There you go.
What a shot.
Geez… um…
Get 'em off the streets, right?
I've met guys that went to prison
that said that was the best thing for them
because I got out of the drugs
to see how messed I was.
I'm not saying that's the answer but it…
Because they can't
take them off the streets
then you get this…
Which is just like…
highly unsustainable.
We're circling around here but…
I'm just trying to understand
the strategy of the city
like just contain it to this one area?
And let it rip?
I mean I don't know that part.
I don't think
nobody know an answer for that.
[Peter] Yeah, how do you
want to get on that line?
Imagine going on the train here.
We can park right here.
I can wait for you right here
or we can get out and walk
You can wait if you want.
I'm sure you do.
I'll be quick, you gotta move quick
with the camera in this zone.
[sirens blare]
Geez these guys using over there.
City of Philly,
whoever has the power to do something.
time to get to work
'cause two years ago it was like this
You can see needles in between the tracks.
What's up, you guys
-You guys live in the neighborhood?
-Yes.
How is it right now?
Um… very…
If you living here it feels alright
but a lot of sh*t happens.
-It's rough, huh?
I mean walking by all the drugs every day.
Yeah, and all these needles
on the floor everywhere.
-Needles on the floor?
Okay,
what would you say to the city leadership
if you could speak to them directly?
Kamala Harris, get your sh*t together.
Because this sh*t is insane.
How y'all got birds
and everything past Gerard?
Looking clean,
y’all got this sh*t looking a mess.
Fix this sh*t please!
Y'all making unnecessary…
Y'all got contractors working out here
doing piece of sh*t job in these streets.
Like I really don't understand but…
I've been told everything is…
-You girls watch out for yourselves, right?
Take care of yourselves.
Yeah, guys.
This is…
-Yeah, that was gross, huh?
-That's nasty.
That's nasty.
So effed up beyond belief.
'Cause it doesn't have to be that way.
This needs a lot of energy.
A lot of people are helping, right?
Feeding people, trying to get people
off the streets I got it but
it's more of a legislative thing.
You need government to come in
with some muscle and be like okay…
This doesn't work.
We're gonna enforce the law.
You can't do fent on the streets
with kids walking around.
You're gonna go to rehab and treatment
or you're going to prison.
I don't know
another option really to be honest.
That's the best I can come up with.
I'm oversimplifying it.
I've never seen a place on this place,
85 countries that I've been to,
with less humanity than that.
Doesn't mean there aren't
people really trying
but energetically it's…
Do you feel it at all or no?
Are you just immune to it at this point?
Yeah, it's something to be numb to.
Immune. It's just normal.
-Right, it's been normalized.
So people from Philly wouldn't
think twice about it unless it's like
it has to be the mayor, the woman,
the other woman she says, the mayor.
Now there was a point in time
when the mayor did get into office
that street was clean of people
and trash for about a couple days.
And then people went back out there.
She was right. It was cleaned up.
but it wasn't for that long.
-And it's crazy, not long ago,
these were blue collar jobs
working at the factory,
working class neighborhood,
and I also want to mention, you guys,
I'm showing you the nice part
Rittenhouse Park area
and then the hardest hitting part,
Kensington.
There's a lot of middle class.
When you fly into Philly
it's suburb, after suburb, after suburb.
And not showing that today.
So it's not like
there are just these two extremes.
It's most in the middle actually.
But we're staying in Philly today.
Outside of Philly there are neighborhoods
that are way nicer than Rittenhouse Park.
There are a lot of standard classic
Americana housing developments
for as far as the eye can see.
[Malcom] From this bridge right here,
you gon' start seeing
the difference in housing.
Cleanliness of it.
It's just gonna look different.
-It just totally changes?
-Yes.
So now we going to
the direction of Fishtown.
Even these is new apartments over here.
-Right, that's wild.
-Over there on the left side.
-Yep.
-So this wasn't like this long ago?
-No!
-This was pretty rundown?
-Yes.
Right here on that brick wall
where the graffiti is at
that's how it was looking.
But even these buildings next to it,
that's all new.
-The streets are clean.
Totally different reality.
-You can see on the right,
that's how they lived before.
-Right.
[Malcom] You'll start seeing more
buildings getting built.
New residential townhouses
to luxury apartments.
These probably like minimum $3,000.
-Delaware Avenue.
-And the river's right over there, right?
-Yes.
-Okay.
So that's the draw? Nice waterfront?
[Peter] This place took off, huh?
-You'd be surprised how fast
they built that. Took a couple years.
Another Philly staple.
[customers chattering]
[Peter] Thank you.
So we went Cooper's Sharp cheese,
light onion.
-Know what we forgot?
-What's that?
That was behind the counter
that she told us, ketchup.
We forgot the ketchup.
But in Philly this is
one of my favorite Cheesesteak places.
-Wow.
On a seeded roll.
Seeded roll, look at that, Malcom, nice.
Look at that.
Oh! Yeah!
-See meat ratio to the bread.
-Let me know what you think.
-Cheers, brother.
-Mmm.
-We ain't get napkins either.
Thank you, bro.
-Del Rossi's can't miss.
And so the bread,
they make their own bread, right?
Tastes like it.
And the bread's
what helps the cheesesteak too.
Like I woulda ordered, man,
you know if this is gonna be
a good cheesesteak 'cause the bread's soft.
Oh, yeah.
This is the best one I've had.
I did…
cheesesteak last time.
It was good but this is
fire.
[horn honks aggressively]
-Brother.
-[hands slap]
And I also want to aim people
to your fashion.
-Right, right, right.
-Show your phone.
Your last name is Savage?
My last name is Savage.
That is so savage.
High quality brand.
-Organic materials?
-Organic cotton, 100%.
Some of it made in the USA, you're trying
to get all of it made in the USA.
That's one of my goals.
Have everything made here in the US.
Okay, Malcom, you're a legend, buddy.
Thanks for that. Good times, buddy.
Lucked out with Malcom.
Now back in the center of the city.
And this party is starting
with the players here.
I guess they're going on the bus right now,
the Croatia players.
-[jazz music]
-[crowd cheering]
[music and cheering]
Guys, it's awesome.
Such a great feeling. So festive.
Everyone's fired up.
Good energy.
I flew in last night with the plan
of shooting the video tomorrow
and then last night
I found out this was happening
so I was like
I gotta shoot the video today.
Capture this energy on the streets.
[man] Two, zero.
[Peter] That's the best picture ever.
You guys want it up and down or sideways?
All right, father and son out
trying to get tickets.
-No luck, huh?
-No luck.
Sold out.
Hopefully we find something.
You never know.
-Who you guys going for?
-I'm here for Croatia, how about you?
I want Croatia to win but I just want
to watch any World Cup game.
You just want to get into any cup game?
Oh, man.
[tribal music]
[crowd cheering]
[cheering continues]
[Peter] Full circle, guys.
Philadelphia.
Not an easy place to define
but such a beautiful interesting vibrant
delicious, sad,
gritty…
And we did even see 97% of it today.
I did my best
to show you as much as possible.
Starting point of our
beautiful and amazing country.
If you're watching the day
this video drops on the fourth
happy birthday fellow Americans.
It's our birthday as a country.
Such a spectacular experiment.
Something so wild and different.
And we've endured 250.
To many, many more.
Thanks for coming along on that journey.
Until the next one.
[drums playing]